So, what are we doing here?
这节课是干什么的？
What is this all about?
会学习哪些知识？
As we heard about earlier,
之前已经提到
our work in this lesson builds upon previous lessons.
这节课以之前的几节课为基础
While we'll still develop trading strategies with
我们根据股票池创建了交易策略
large baskets of stocks and use optimization to
并利用优化工具
find combinations of weights on stocks to
得出能够在给定风险水平下
seek the highest return for a given level of risk,
达到最高收益率的股票权重组合
we'll now learn how to develop models of portfolio returns
现在我们将学习如何创建投资组合收益率和风险模型
and risk and add these into our optimization framework.
并将这些因素加入到优化框架中来
Before, we always talked about the distribution of
之前我们一直提到未来对数收益率分布
future log returns and it's mean and standard deviation like these were numbers,
以及该分布的均值和标准差
we can just read off of a list somewhere.
它们就好像可以从某个列表中读取的数字一样
But in general, this is not the case.
但事实并非如此
Otherwise, all this would be easy.
要不然一切太简单了
In addition, we aren't going to explicitly model returns in the way you might expect.
此外 我们不会像你预期的那样明确创建收益率模型
The problem with explicit estimation of returns is that these estimates are very
明确估算收益率会导致这些估算值
noisy and noise causes
有很多噪点
unnecessary trading which we want to avoid because trades are costly.
噪点会导致不必要的交易 而我们需要避免不必要的交易 因为交易成本非常高
Instead, we will focus on what Jonathan mentioned earlier.
我们将侧重于 Jonathan 之前提到的几个方面
Drivers of mean returns and drivers of
即均值收益率的推动因素和波动率的推动因素
volatility and these will be the bases of our model.
这些推动因素将是模型的基础
Drivers of mean returns are alpha factors and drivers of volatility or risk factors.
均值收益率推动因素属于 alpha 因子 波动率推动因素属于风险因子
We'll come up with a way to quantify these concepts.
我们将介绍衡量这些因子的方式
In the next few lessons,
在接下来的几节课
we'll learn about factors,
我们将学习因子
how to create and improve them,
学习如何创建和改进因子
and how they fit into the model.
以及如何拟合到模型中
We will also explore advanced portfolio optimization using factors.
我们还将使用因子探索高阶投资组合优化方法
We've actually seen some ideas for factors earlier
在这门课程中 我们之前见过因子概念
in this course without explicitly calling them factors.
只是没有明确称为因子
For example, factors can be based on momentum, or fundamental information.
例如 因子可能基于动量或基本面信息
When we can process the data in such a way that they have the potential
如果数据经过处理后
to provide predictive information about the future movement of stocks,
能够提供关于股票未来走势的预测信息
we call these factors.
那么我们称之为因子
But what is a factor?
什么是因子？
A factor is a list of numerical values one assign to each stock in
因子是我们为股票池中的
our stock universe that is derived to potentially be
每支股票分配的一系列数值
predictive of an aspect of the performance of the stocks in the future.
这些值能够对股票的未来业绩作出预测
In essence, factors are signals that help suggest where to place bets in a portfolio of
其实因子是帮助你决定投资组合中不同股票的权重
stocks and further suggest what the relative magnitudes of those bets should be.
以及不同股票间相对投资金额的大小的信号
Factors are the basis of quantitative portfolio management,
因子是量化投资管理的基础
as the search for effective trading strategies starts
因为寻找有效交易策略
with a search for factors that drive stock movements.
首先需要寻找推动股票变化的因子
This lesson will introduce you to an example of a factor and show you how to
这节课将介绍一个示例因子
standardize it so that it can be interpreted
并演示如何标准化它
as a set of weights for a theoretical portfolio.
从而能够将其解析为理论投资组合的权重集合
After that, we'll walk you through an open source Python library,
然后 我们将介绍一个开源 Python 库 Zipline
Zipline which we'll use throughout the module.
我们将在整个模块中用到该库
You'll also use it in the project to create and evaluate factors encode.
你还将在实战项目中使用该库创建和评估因子
Zipline is a Pythonic algorithmic trading library.
Zipline 是一个 Python 算法交易库
It's an event-driven system for back-testing.
它是一个由事件推动的回溯测试系统
If you start work at a fund or a bank,
如果你在基金或银行工作
it's likely that you will learn proprietary software packages that are
很有可能会学习公司自己开发的
built in-house and these will be unique to the firm that you work at.
专属定制软件包
Learning how to use the open source packages in this program,
学习如何使用这门课程中介绍的开源软件包
will give you practice in learning and using
将使你从实践角度学习如何使用定制库
custom libraries such as the ones that you may use on the job.
例如在工作中可能会用到的库
By the end of this lesson,
学完这节课后
you'll have hands on practice with implementing
你将在代码中实现你的首个因子
your first factor in code which will serve as a foundation for the rest of the module.
并且为这个模块的剩余内容打下基础